Danny Woodford

7 Chartwell Ct Freehold, NJ | 908-907-8680 | <u>Daniel.woodford.g@gmail.com</u> Github | Linkedin | https://danny-woodford.firebaseapp.com/

Summary

JavaScript and Ruby full-stack/UI developer with keen proficiency for visuals. Diverse background includes custom craftsmanship for luxury renovations from inception to finished project. Created the first cross-discipline collaboration event between DevOps, data science, and UX/UI at the Flatiron School. My passions include art and stand-up comedy reinforcing creativity and courage. History includes team leadership while working on cross-functional projects with specialists. Highly effective communicator collaborating on integrated projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, CSS, SASS, HTML, HTML5, CANVAS, Greenstock, Photoshop, Sketch, jQuery, Node.js, Three.js, REST API's, MySQL, Git, Docker, SQL Server, C#

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Spotify 3D music Visualizer - Github | Demo

- Utilized Three.js to create a 3d environment the user can move around with ease
- Set up Spotify's web playback SDK to allow login and music streaming from any premium account
- Mapped song analytics and features from Spotify's API and synchronize data to playback
- Built with react and has an unused rails backend to allow for future expansion

Ziehbare Stimme Leinwand - Github

This Todo list app, apart from having full CRUD functionality, is designed specifically to frustrate the user.

- Built with react for its modular nature with a rails backend to persist user data
- Implemented konva.js (HTML5 Canvas JavaScript framework) to improve the efficiency of dynamic background and enabled Tenserflow to allow for voice commands

NOTFLIX Github | Demo

Netflix inspired app is a library of TV shows and movies found on youtube with a smart clean look.

- Enacted vision of app with a Ruby on Rails frontend and backend
- Expressed design concept with CSS/SCSS for the first time

EXPERIENCE

Entry-Level Software Engineer, Summitworks Technology, South Plainfield, NJ

Summitworks provides custom application development using existing and emerging technologies.

February 2020-current

 cross-functional exposure to C# and SQL Server while further advancing my skills in JavaScript working with dedicated professionals

Sub-contractor/carpenter, NJRAS Group, Freehold, Nj

This business offers to preserve & protect bank foreclosures. Also home improvement & rehab.

May 2018-August 2019

 Renovated houses from demolition to a final product managing timely execution of project plan while collaborating with 4-5 other workers

Carpenter's Assistant, Ariante Custom Builders inc, Brielle, Nj March 2018-May 2018

Apprenticed for an experienced craftsman who mentored detailed, highly skilled finishes

High-end Restaurant Industry including **Char**, **Robinson's Ale House**, **La Cipollina**, Across NJ **2013 spring- 2018 fall**

• Worked from entry-level dishwasher, to mid-level management, coordinating team engagement

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

August 2019-December 2019

Full-Stack Software Development

Rowan University, Glassboro, Ni

September 2013-May 2015

Coursework completed towards a Bachelor of Science Degree in Mechanical Engineering